# Dan Bryan

I am a creative minded individual with 20 years of experience in information technology. I'm accomplished in infrastructure, research, and security. I am passionate about cloud technologies and automation. I'm extremely experienced in solutions engineering and troubleshooting. I'm confident in my ability to lead and communicate with others. I have an exceptional understanding how technologies relate to one another and enjoy solving complex technical problems.

# Top Technical Skills

Amazon Web Services, Automation, Terraform, Cloudformation.

# Education

**1998-Present** Community College; Various courses of interest, no degree.

(expected) Microsoft, Networking, Cyber Security

2005-2010 USAF Technical School and Training; Keesler AFB, Eglin AFB

Communications: Networking, Voice, Systems, Transmissions

# Certifications

- AWS DevOps Professional V64WBJVKCBR4QGCE
- AWS Certified Developer Associate GB47ENDCKMBE1RCT
- (ISC)<sup>2</sup> CISSP 410338
- CCNA Security CSCO11709829 (previously held)
- CompTIA Network+ COMP001008999716 (legacy)
- CompTIA A+ COMP0010621927 (legacy)

# Experience

Owner @ Bryanlabs: October 2018 - Present

As a small business owner, I learned that I also love business. Here are some of those experiences:

- Understanding US tax code has become a passion of mine. Simple things like, using form 2553
  to elect scorp status to split income into a W2 and K1 to save on FICA. These IRS forms are very
  similar to the Technical RFC's I read and contributed to back when I was a PKI engineer in love
  with RFC 2560. I enjoy this legalistic aspect of both protocols, and the legal system.
- I learned alot about investments too. The fact that one could use their scorp to adopt a solo 401K plan, then have that plan purchase an LLC, and then do self directed investing. Back in 2020 I created Self Directed 401K, IRA, HSA LLCs, and made crypto investments.
- Being the manager of these 4 companies required that I learn how to do the book keeping too. I learned all about how use systems that manage payroll and books. I use Quick Books Online

to manage 6 different sets of books. I put a lot of effort into creating clean simple to understand P&Ls, balance sheets, cash flows.

• I have experience writing proposals, my company even won a grant this year from the ethereum foundation based on a proposal i submitted.

#### Defi Engineer @ Bryanlabs: October 2020 - Present

During my time at Bryanlabs, I also had a focus on using Defi:

- I started off by learning about ethereum and it's need to migrate to proof of stake. Being technical I decided to become an ethereum2 validator. I participated in Medalla, Spadina, Zinken, and Pyrmont testnets. I also was part of the Serenity Launch and still am an active validaor. https://app.poap.xyz/scan/danb.eth
- A college and me submitted and won a grant to the ethereum foundation for the eth-docker project. http://eth-docker.net/ https://github.com/eth2-educators/eth2-docker and we still actively develop it
- On Ethereum I read white papers, and used many Dapps to include. AAVE, Uniswap,1inch catnip, synthetix, dYdX, opensea
- On Binance Smart Chain I used Pancake Swap, Venus, autofarm, pancakebunny, jetfuel finance, yeild watch, linear finance
- I have run a Theta guardian node, and edge node
- I have provided liquidity on several decentralized Exchanges, and participated in various farms.
- I'v spent a lot of time keeping up with the hype and trends too. Daily consumer of crypto banter, elliotrades, dan teaches crypto, altcoin daily, bankless.
- Lately I have been very interested in Cardano and am excited for their alonzo launch introducing smart contracts.
- I have done some work on chainlink as well. Mostly from an Architecture standpoint. A college of mine won 2nd place in the chainlink olympics, and consulted me to help design the AWS Architecture.

**AWS Subject Matter Expert @ Bryanlabs:** October 2018 - Present During my time at Bryanlabs I also have been recognized by AWS as a subject matter expert in Devops.:

- Attended DOP Workshops in Atlanta, Chicago, Seattle.
- · Attended various Remote DOP workshops.
- https://www.credly.com/users/dan-bryan/badges

#### Devops Engineer @ Bryanlabs: October 2018 - Present

Founded in 2018, Bryanlabs focuses on automation and development in AWS environments.:

- Lead the development of a terraform project to quickly provision a managed development environments in AWS.
- Created Terraform modules for deploying an AWS networking solution across multiple AWS accounts.
- Created Terraform module for deploying Microsoft Active Directory on EC2 in AWS.
- Oversaw the development of many other terraform modules to include, AWS DNS, Governance Software, Tenable Security Center, AMI Factory, and Certificate management.
- Created CI/CD pipeline in gitlab to validate terraform code, deploy new features to a staging environment, and run unit tests before accepting.

- Integrated Terragrunt into terraform deployment strategy to keep modules dry, and facilitate orchestration of module deployment.
- Blogger on AWS automation and development.
- Question writer/external SME for AWS DevOps Professional Certification Exam.
- Created complex IAM policies to align with NIST 800-53 standards like HIPAA, PCI, ISO...
- Created CFT remediation to ensure all non whitelisted s3 buckets and objects remain private.
- Created CFT remediation to ensure all non whitelisted RDS / Redshift clusters remain private.
- Created CFT remediation to ensure EBS and RDS snapshots remain private.
- Created CFT remediation to ensure users could only use the AWS API during office hours and from trusted locations.
- Assisted client with moving a public RDS instance to a private instance and reconfiguring the network, so lambda could communicate with the private DB.
- Created custom AWS health API tool, to publish all health events to a clients rest API.

# Freelance DevOps Engineer @ Toptal October 2018 - Present

Toptal is an exclusive network of the top freelance software developers, designers, finance experts, and project managers in the world. Top companies rely on Toptal freelancers for their most important projects.:

- Provided AWS Well Architected Reviews for Key Toptal clients.
- Provided AWS Consulting to Toptal Developers.
- Technical consultant for developing a new business proposal for a key Toptal client.

# DevOps Engineer @ Applied Insight October 2016 - July 2020

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Automated AWS infrastructure using CloudFormation and terraform.
- Developed various GoLang micro-services focused on integration with AWS, Microsoft, and SafeNet APIs.
- Deployed Serverless website using CodeStar, CodeCommit, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, S3, Lambda (GoLang), API Gateway, CloudFront.
- Engineered Kubernetes cluster focused on streaming applications using X11 over SSH.
- Presented Automated event analysis solution at AWS re:invent Non-Profit Hackathon. Using Twitter API, Rekognition, Step Functions, and Lambda.
- Engineered Appstream 2.0 solution to provide multi-user application streaming over HTML5.
- Integrated Amazon SSM solution to provide Equipment inventory and Patch compliance.
- Engineered API Gateway to provide equipment info from DynamoDB via Lambda.
- Engineered AMI factory using EC2 Simple Systems Manager.
- Automated system states for Linux and Windows servers using SaltStack.
- Developed various shell / python scripts / Lambda functions to automate AWS maintenance, rotate/share AMIs, bootstrap servers, identify non-compliant servers.
- Deployed AWS Elastic Container Service and dockerized various services.
- · Audited security of web-services and ensured they followed PKI best practices.
- Continuously researched and prototyped latest AWS services for consideration of environment evolution.
- Engineered and maintained various MFA/SSO technologies including; SafeNet and YubiKey.
- Deployed various web services like Jira, Confluence, Gitlab, Teradici, Windows/cups printserver, and Squid proxy.

#### Security Engineer @ Engineering Solutions, Inc October 2011 - September 2016

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Provided leadership, training and project management for 3 PKI Engineers.
- Provided subject matter expert guidance for customers interfacing with PKI Technologies.
- Designed technical and operational security components by integrating Elasticseach, Logstash, and Kibana to obtain a high level analytical view of the information service.
- Lead development of enterprise revocation service security architecture.
- Lead enterprise revocation service through certification and accreditation.
- Accredited and deployed servers via physical, virtual, and cloud based mediums.
- Developed multiple tools enabling admins and developers to interface with PKI technologies.
- Coordinated PKI configurations with desktop providers and software distribution centers.
- Recommended physical, administrative and technical controls to ensure high availability of enterprise PKI service using BIG-IP F5's.
- Recommended and implemented Intrusion detection, access control, and auditing of PKI services.
- Lead security planning, assessment, and risk management activities for PKI services using DISA STIGs, Retina, Nessus technologies.
- Provided system security engineering guidance to Enterprise Lync/Desktop server teams as a subject matter expert in certificate revocation technologies.
- Interacted with high-level stakeholders of Engineering Review Board defining standard OCSP policies and objectives ensuring availability across the enterprise.

# Technical Consultant @ Self Employed June 2010 - September 2011

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Participated in SAIC's MD Cyber challenge incorporating computer defense and offense strategies. Implementing STIGs, and performing vulnerability assessments with Nessus / Metasploit / Armitage.
- Participated in Deloitte's National Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition with Howard Community College.
- Deployed CISCO ASA 5505, enabled AnyConnect VPN solution with active directory authentication as well as configured firewall services for a DMZ and internal LAN.
- Attended Hacker Space events frequently, including seminars, presenting at conferences, and entering capture the flag challenges.
- Attended various classes related to network security: VPN, IDS, Firewall, Pentesting.
- Self-pursuit of CCNP Route, Switch, and Tshoot via Howard Community College.
- Self-pursuit of Python training via CBT nuggets.
- Self-pursuit of Oracle Database 11g SQL Fundamentals training via CBT nuggets.
- Installed, configured desktop, server, and network components.
- Resolved issues with mobile devices, desktop, printers, software, and network appliances.
- Provided Hands on training with new hardware and software technologies.

#### Network Integration Specialist @ United States Air Force June 2004 - June 2010

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Determined equipment, and configuration requirements as well as provided guidance for installation of Communications technology components. (multiplexors, PBX, Voice, VoIP, Network).
- · Assisted with a Squadron site relocation communications design; coordinated relocation with ser-

vice providers to ensure availability of critical systems during transition.

- Kept detailed documentation of network, telecommunication, and transmission circuits.
- Provided cryptography solutions for missions, key issuance, renewal, and application.
- Developed tools allowing operators to automate common tasks.
- Provided computer systems support for squadron. Installed software, fixed connectivity issues, diagnosed hardware issues.
- Created and maintained a public website for the Air control Squadron.
- Graduated Airman Leadership School and took on the role of supervisor providing performance reports and career training for network system employees.

#### Pharmacy Technician @ Safeway October 2002 - May 2004

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Provided technical assistance with medical devices.
- · Acted as technical support liaison with Safeway Help desk.
- Input customer personal and medical data into computer software.
- Ensured customer PII was protected in accordance with HIPPA regulations.

# System Administrator @ LibertyStone Inc September 2001 - September 2002

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- · Managed Windows domain services including active directory, DHCP, DNS, IIS.
- Built and configured Windows 98/XP/2000 desktop/servers.
- Resolved hardware issues with computers, printers, telephones and fax machines.
- Built Cat-5 cables, ran wires, and diagnosed network connectivity issues.
- Performed website development for 4 websites using dreamweaver.
- · Developed various tools using visual basic.

### System Administrator @ James German and Associates March 2001 - September 2001

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Performed OS and Software deployments.
- Engineered Local Area Network and Internet connectivity.
- · Installed and Configured fax machines, printers.

#### System Administrator @ AM/PM Computer Services, Inc. September 2000 - March 2001

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Built and configured Windows 98 desktops.
- Resolved hardware issues with computers, printers, telephones and fax machines.
- Built Cat-5 cables, ran wires, and diagnosed network connectivity issues.

#### Technical Consultant @ Self Employed. June 1998 - September 2000

Engineered AWS environments, created automation solutions, and prototyped new services:

- Managed RedHat 5 (Hurricane) Linux server running apache.
- Developed and managed website for independent pharmacy in Cloverly MD.
- Performed Cat-5 cable management including cable termination and routing.

- Installed and configured Internet Service Provider Routers.
- Configured Internet connection sharing and Home networking.
- Attended '2600 Hacker Quarterly' Meetings in Baltimore.

dan@bryanlabs.net • +01 (443) 569 4343 Laurel, MD, USA